<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<quiz>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name><text>FA2-Ch10-S1-01-PRK6.4</text></name>
    <questiontext format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>When posting an invoice for car repairs, $870 was entered on the correct side of the motor expenses account. The invoice was for $780.<br><br>What correction should be made to the motor expenses account?</p>]]></text></questiontext>
    <generalfeedback format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>The following is GenAI explanations, use with caution.The motor expenses account is an expense account, which normally has a debit balance. The correct debit entry should have been $780. However, an amount of $870 was debited. This means the account was overstated by $870 - $780 = $90. To correct this overstatement, the motor expenses account must be reduced by $90. Reducing a debit balance is achieved by making a credit entry. Therefore, the motor expenses account should be credited with $90.<br><br>Why other options are incorrect:<br>A. Debiting $90 would further increase the expense balance, making the error worse.<br>C. Debiting $1,650 is incorrect; it seems to be the sum of the two figures ($870 + $780), which is not relevant to the correction.<br>D. Crediting $1,650 is an incorrect amount and would drastically understate the expense.</p>]]></text></generalfeedback>
    <defaultgrade>1.00</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>true</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>abc</answernumbering>
    <correctfeedback format="html"><text>Your answer is correct.</text></correctfeedback>
    <partiallycorrectfeedback format="html"><text>Your answer is partially correct.</text></partiallycorrectfeedback>
    <incorrectfeedback format="html"><text>Your answer is incorrect.</text></incorrectfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>Debit $90</p>]]></text></answer>
    <answer fraction="100.00000" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>Credit $90</p>]]></text></answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>Debit $1,650</p>]]></text></answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>Credit $1,650</p>]]></text></answer>
  </question>
  <question type="cloze">
    <name><text>FA2-Ch10-S1-02-PRK6.5</text></name>
    <questiontext format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>Swirly is reviewing the trade receivables account in her general ledger and has noted some discrepancies:<br><br>Draft balance on trade receivables account $35,776<br>Bank receipt from a credit customer which has not yet been recorded $452<br>Invoice in respect of a credit sale which had been omitted from the records $900<br><br>What is the correct balance of trade receivables to be reported on the statement of financial position?</p><p>Answer: {1:NUMERICAL:=36224:0}</p>]]></text></questiontext>
    <generalfeedback format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>The following is GenAI explanations, use with caution.To find the correct balance of trade receivables, we need to adjust the draft balance for the discrepancies noted.<br><br>1.  **Draft balance:** $35,776 (This is the starting point).<br>2.  **Bank receipt from a customer ($452):** A receipt of cash from a customer reduces the amount they owe. This transaction was not recorded, so we must deduct it from the receivables balance. ($35,776 - $452 = $35,324).<br>3.  **Omitted credit sale invoice ($900):** A credit sale increases the amount customers owe. This invoice was omitted, so we must add it to the receivables balance. ($35,324 + $900 = $36,224).<br><br>Calculation:<br>Draft balance: $35,776<br>Less: Unrecorded bank receipt: ($452)<br>Add: Omitted credit sale: +$900<br>Correct balance: **$36,224**</p>]]></text></generalfeedback>
    <defaultgrade>1.00</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name><text>FA2-Ch10-S1-03-PRK6.6</text></name>
    <questiontext format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>Ferrero made an error when he posted a purchase invoice to the accounting records. He posted $74,865 to the debit side of the purchases account. The correct amount was $74,685.<br><br>How is the trial balance affected by this error?</p>]]></text></questiontext>
    <generalfeedback format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>The following is GenAI explanations, use with caution.The error involves an incorrect amount being posted to one side of the double entry. The correct double entry for the purchase invoice of $74,685 would be:<br>Debit Purchases account: $74,685<br>Credit Trade Payables account: $74,685<br><br>However, the purchases account was debited with $74,865. Assuming the credit entry to trade payables was made correctly for $74,685, the debit side of the trial balance is overstated by the difference: $74,865 - $74,685 = $180.<br><br>As a result, the total of the debit balances in the trial balance will be $180 higher than the total of the credit balances. Therefore, the total of the debit balances will exceed the total of the credit balances.<br><br>Why other options are incorrect:<br>A & B: The trial balance totals will not agree because a different amount was posted to the debit and credit sides.<br>D: The credit balances will not exceed the debit balances; the error caused the debit total to be higher.</p>]]></text></generalfeedback>
    <defaultgrade>1.00</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>true</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>abc</answernumbering>
    <correctfeedback format="html"><text>Your answer is correct.</text></correctfeedback>
    <partiallycorrectfeedback format="html"><text>Your answer is partially correct.</text></partiallycorrectfeedback>
    <incorrectfeedback format="html"><text>Your answer is incorrect.</text></incorrectfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>The total of the debit balances and the total of the credit balances will agree, but will be overstated</p>]]></text></answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>The total of the debit balances and the total of the credit balances will agree, but will be understated</p>]]></text></answer>
    <answer fraction="100.00000" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>The total of the debit balances will exceed the total of the credit balances</p>]]></text></answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>The total of the credit balances will exceed the total of the debit balances</p>]]></text></answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name><text>FA2-Ch10-S1-04-PRK6.9</text></name>
    <questiontext format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>A suspense account shows a credit balance of $130.<br><br>This balance could be due to which of the following?</p>]]></text></questiontext>
    <generalfeedback format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>The following is GenAI explanations, use with caution.A credit balance of $130 in the suspense account means that the total debits in the trial balance were $130 more than the total credits. The suspense account was credited to make the trial balance balance.<br><br>Let's analyze the options:<br>A. Omitting a sale is an error of omission. Both the debit (to trade receivables) and the credit (to sales) would be missed, so the trial balance would still balance.<br>B. **Recording a purchase of $130 twice in the purchases account:** The normal entry for a purchase is Debit Purchases, Credit Payables. If the debit to the purchases account was made twice, but the credit to payables was made only once, the total debits would be $130 higher than the total credits. This would create the need for a $130 credit in the suspense account. This matches the scenario.<br>C. Failing to write off a debt is an error of omission. The entry (Debit Irrecoverable Debt Expense, Credit Trade Receivables) was completely missed, so the trial balance would still balance.<br>D. Recording an electricity bill paid by debiting the bank and crediting electricity is an error of principle/commission. The correct entry is Debit Electricity, Credit Bank. Both entries made were incorrect, but a debit and a credit of equal value were still posted, so the trial balance would still balance.</p>]]></text></generalfeedback>
    <defaultgrade>1.00</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>true</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>abc</answernumbering>
    <correctfeedback format="html"><text>Your answer is correct.</text></correctfeedback>
    <partiallycorrectfeedback format="html"><text>Your answer is partially correct.</text></partiallycorrectfeedback>
    <incorrectfeedback format="html"><text>Your answer is incorrect.</text></incorrectfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>Omitting a sale of $130 from the trade receivables account</p>]]></text></answer>
    <answer fraction="100.00000" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>Recording a purchase of $130 twice in the purchases account</p>]]></text></answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>Failing to write off an irrecoverable debt of $130</p>]]></text></answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>Recording an electricity bill paid of $65 by debiting the bank account and crediting the electricity account.</p>]]></text></answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name><text>FA2-Ch10-S1-05-PRK6.10</text></name>
    <questiontext format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>When Nini extracted her trial balance, the total of the debit balances exceeded the total of the credit balances by $1,000. She opened a suspense account to make the two totals equal. She then discovered that an invoice received for property repairs for $1,500 was entered as $500 on the credit side of the property repairs account.<br><br>What is the revised balance on the suspense account when Nini corrects this error?</p>]]></text></questiontext>
    <generalfeedback format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>The following is GenAI explanations, use with caution.Let's break this down step-by-step:<br><br>1.  **Initial Suspense Account Balance:** The debit balances exceeded the credit balances by $1,000. To make the trial balance agree, a credit of $1,000 was entered into the suspense account. So, the opening balance is $1,000 credit.<br><br>2.  **Analyze the Error:** An invoice for property repairs of $1,500 should have been a DEBIT to the property repairs expense account. Instead, it was entered as a $500 CREDIT to that account.<br>    *   The debit side is understated by $1,500 (the correct debit was missed).<br>    *   The credit side is overstated by $500 (an incorrect credit was posted).<br><br>3.  **Correction Journal Entry:** To correct this, we must:<br>    *   Reverse the incorrect credit: Debit Property Repairs $500.<br>    *   Post the correct debit: Debit Property Repairs $1,500.<br>    *   The total debit to correct the property repairs account is $500 + $1,500 = $2,000.<br>    *   The other side of this correction entry goes to the suspense account.<br>    *   The journal entry is: Debit Property Repairs $2,000, Credit Suspense Account $2,000.<br><br>4.  **Revised Suspense Account Balance:**<br>    *   Opening balance: $1,000 credit.<br>    *   Add the credit from the correction: +$2,000 credit.<br>    *   Closing balance: $1,000 + $2,000 = **$3,000 credit**.</p>]]></text></generalfeedback>
    <defaultgrade>1.00</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>true</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>abc</answernumbering>
    <correctfeedback format="html"><text>Your answer is correct.</text></correctfeedback>
    <partiallycorrectfeedback format="html"><text>Your answer is partially correct.</text></partiallycorrectfeedback>
    <incorrectfeedback format="html"><text>Your answer is incorrect.</text></incorrectfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>$Nil</p>]]></text></answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>$2,000 debit</p>]]></text></answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>$2,000 credit</p>]]></text></answer>
    <answer fraction="100.00000" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>$3,000 credit</p>]]></text></answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name><text>FA2-Ch10-S1-06-PRK6.11</text></name>
    <questiontext format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>Don received a bank receipt for $950 from his insurance company in settlement of a claim for repairs to a van. The accounts assistant recorded the bank receipt correctly in the bank general ledger account, but did not complete the double entry. The total of the trial balance did not agree and a suspense account was opened to record the difference.<br><br>What journal entry is required to eliminate the balance on the suspense account?</p>]]></text></questiontext>
    <generalfeedback format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>The following is GenAI explanations, use with caution.1.  **Analyze the initial entry and error:** A bank receipt of $950 was correctly recorded. This means the bank account was debited by $950 (Debit Bank $950). The double entry was not completed, meaning the corresponding credit entry was missed.<br><br>2.  **Effect on Trial Balance:** Because there was a debit of $950 without a corresponding credit, the total debit balances exceeded the total credit balances by $950. To make the trial balance agree, a suspense account was opened with a $950 credit balance.<br><br>3.  **Identify the missing credit:** The receipt was from an insurance company for van repairs. This is an insurance claim receipt. It can be treated either as 'Insurance Claim Income' or, more commonly, as a reduction of the related expense, 'Van Repairs'. The options suggest crediting 'Van Repairs'. This credit entry reduces the total van repair expense previously recorded.<br><br>4.  **Formulate the correction journal entry:** The missing credit entry needs to be posted (Credit Van Repairs $950). To clear the suspense account, which has a $950 credit balance, we must debit it. Therefore, the journal entry is:<br>    **DEBIT Suspense account $950**<br>    **CREDIT Van repairs $950**<br>This eliminates the suspense account balance and correctly records the other half of the original transaction.</p>]]></text></generalfeedback>
    <defaultgrade>1.00</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>true</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>abc</answernumbering>
    <correctfeedback format="html"><text>Your answer is correct.</text></correctfeedback>
    <partiallycorrectfeedback format="html"><text>Your answer is partially correct.</text></partiallycorrectfeedback>
    <incorrectfeedback format="html"><text>Your answer is incorrect.</text></incorrectfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>DEBIT Suspense account $950<br>CREDIT Insurance $950<br>Being correction of an error of omission</p>]]></text></answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>DEBIT Insurance $950<br>CREDIT Suspense account $950<br>Being correction of an error of omission</p>]]></text></answer>
    <answer fraction="100.00000" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>DEBIT Suspense account $950<br>CREDIT Van repairs $950<br>Being correction of an error of omission</p>]]></text></answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>DEBIT Van repairs $950<br>CREDIT Suspense account $950<br>Being correction of an error of omission</p>]]></text></answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name><text>FA2-Ch10-S1-07-PRK6.13</text></name>
    <questiontext format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>Dandy trial balance includes a suspense account with a credit balance of $280. She has discovered that a supplier's invoice for $140 was entered twice in the purchases account and trade payables account.<br><br>What is the balance on the suspense account after this error is corrected?</p>]]></text></questiontext>
    <generalfeedback format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>The following is GenAI explanations, use with caution.1.  **Initial Suspense Account Balance:** The suspense account has a credit balance of $280. This means there are other errors causing the trial balance to be imbalanced.<br><br>2.  **Analyze the Discovered Error:** A supplier's invoice of $140 was entered twice. The correct entry is Debit Purchases $140 and Credit Trade Payables $140. Since the entire transaction was duplicated, both the debit and credit sides of the trial balance were increased by an extra $140. This type of error, where a complete transaction is posted twice, does not cause the trial balance totals to disagree.<br><br>3.  **Correction of the Error:** To correct this, one of the duplicated entries must be reversed. The reversal journal entry would be: Debit Trade Payables $140 and Credit Purchases $140. This correction also involves one debit and one credit of equal amounts and therefore does not involve the suspense account.<br><br>4.  **Conclusion:** Since the error itself did not affect the trial balance totals, and the correction for it also does not involve the suspense account, the balance on the suspense account will remain unchanged. The balance remains at **$280 credit**.</p>]]></text></generalfeedback>
    <defaultgrade>1.00</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>true</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>abc</answernumbering>
    <correctfeedback format="html"><text>Your answer is correct.</text></correctfeedback>
    <partiallycorrectfeedback format="html"><text>Your answer is partially correct.</text></partiallycorrectfeedback>
    <incorrectfeedback format="html"><text>Your answer is incorrect.</text></incorrectfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>$Nil</p>]]></text></answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>$140 credit</p>]]></text></answer>
    <answer fraction="100.00000" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>$280 credit</p>]]></text></answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>$420 credit</p>]]></text></answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name><text>FA2-Ch10-S1-08-PRK6.12</text></name>
    <questiontext format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>Which of the following statements is/are correct?<br><br>(i) A separate suspense account should be opened for each error in the ledgers.<br>(ii) A suspense account is sometimes opened to complete postings while more information is sought on a transaction.</p>]]></text></questiontext>
    <generalfeedback format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>The following is GenAI explanations, use with caution.Let's evaluate each statement:<br><br>**(i) A separate suspense account should be opened for each error in the ledgers.**<br>This is **incorrect**. A single suspense account is opened in the general ledger. It holds the net difference between the total debits and total credits of the trial balance, which may be the result of one or multiple errors.<br><br>**(ii) A suspense account is sometimes opened to complete postings while more information is sought on a transaction.**<br>This is **correct**. A suspense account can be used as a temporary holding account for one side of a transaction when the correct account to be debited or credited is not immediately known. Once the information is available, the amount is transferred from the suspense account to the correct account.<br><br>Therefore, only statement (ii) is correct.</p>]]></text></generalfeedback>
    <defaultgrade>1.00</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>true</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>abc</answernumbering>
    <correctfeedback format="html"><text>Your answer is correct.</text></correctfeedback>
    <partiallycorrectfeedback format="html"><text>Your answer is partially correct.</text></partiallycorrectfeedback>
    <incorrectfeedback format="html"><text>Your answer is incorrect.</text></incorrectfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>Only statement (i) is correct</p>]]></text></answer>
    <answer fraction="100.00000" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>Only statement (ii) is correct</p>]]></text></answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>Both statements are correct</p>]]></text></answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>Neither statement is correct</p>]]></text></answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name><text>FA2-Ch10-S1-09-PRK6.14</text></name>
    <questiontext format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>When Jan's trial balance was extracted, the total of the debit balances was $450 less than the total of the credit balances so a suspense account was opened. When she checked, Jan found that:<br><br>(i) A supplier's invoice for $225 had been debited to both the expense account and the trade payables account.<br>(ii) A cash sale for $900 had been omitted from the accounting records.<br><br>When these errors are corrected, what is the balance on the suspense account?</p>]]></text></questiontext>
    <generalfeedback format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>The following is GenAI explanations, use with caution.1.  **Initial Suspense Account Balance:** The debit balances were $450 less than the credit balances. To balance the trial balance, a debit of $450 was entered into the suspense account. So, the opening balance is $450 debit.<br><br>2.  **Analyze Error (i):** A supplier's invoice for $225 was debited to both the expense account (correct) and the trade payables account (incorrect). The trade payables account should have been credited. By debiting it instead, the debit side of the trial balance is overstated by $225, and the credit side is understated by $225. The total effect on the debit side relative to the credit side is an excess debit of $225 + $225 = $450.<br>    *   **Correction for (i):** To fix this, we must credit the trade payables account twice: once to reverse the incorrect debit ($225) and once to post the correct credit ($225). The total credit required is $450. The corresponding debit goes to the suspense account. The journal is: Debit Suspense $450, Credit Trade Payables $450.<br><br>3.  **Analyze Error (ii):** A cash sale of $900 was omitted. This is an error of omission. The double entry (Debit Cash, Credit Sales) was completely missed. This error does not cause the trial balance totals to disagree and therefore does not affect the suspense account.<br><br>4.  **Revised Suspense Account Balance:**<br>    *   Opening balance: $450 debit.<br>    *   Add the debit from the correction of error (i): +$450 debit.<br>    *   Closing balance: $450 + $450 = **$900 debit**.</p>]]></text></generalfeedback>
    <defaultgrade>1.00</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>true</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>abc</answernumbering>
    <correctfeedback format="html"><text>Your answer is correct.</text></correctfeedback>
    <partiallycorrectfeedback format="html"><text>Your answer is partially correct.</text></partiallycorrectfeedback>
    <incorrectfeedback format="html"><text>Your answer is incorrect.</text></incorrectfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100.00000" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>$900 debit</p>]]></text></answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>$900 credit</p>]]></text></answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>$1,800 debit</p>]]></text></answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>$1,800 credit</p>]]></text></answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name><text>FA2-Ch10-S1-10-PRK6.15</text></name>
    <questiontext format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>When Paul's trial balance was extracted, the total of the debit balances was $420 less than the total of the credit balances. He opened a suspense account while he checked the entries. He then found that:<br><br>(i) A cash sale for $80 was entered correctly in the bank general ledger account, but no entry was made in the sales account.<br>(ii) When journal entries were posted to the general ledger, a debit entry of $100 for expenses was incorrectly posted as a credit entry of $700.<br><br>When Paul corrects these errors, what will the balance on his suspense account be?</p>]]></text></questiontext>
    <generalfeedback format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>The following is GenAI explanations, use with caution.1.  **Initial Suspense Account Balance:** Debits were $420 less than credits. A debit of $420 was entered into the suspense account to balance. Opening balance: $420 debit.<br><br>2.  **Analyze Error (i):** A cash sale for $80 was debited to the bank (correct), but the credit to the sales account was missed. This means the credit side of the trial balance is understated by $80. To correct this, we need to credit the sales account. The corresponding debit goes to the suspense account. Correction: Debit Suspense $80, Credit Sales $80.<br><br>3.  **Analyze Error (ii):** A debit entry of $100 for expenses was incorrectly posted as a credit entry of $700. This means the debit side is understated by $100 (the correct debit was missed), and the credit side is overstated by $700 (an incorrect credit was posted). To correct this, we need to: a) post the correct debit of $100, and b) reverse the incorrect credit with a debit of $700. The total debit required is $100 + $700 = $800. The corresponding credit goes to the suspense account. Correction: Debit Expenses $800, Credit Suspense $800.<br><br>4.  **Revised Suspense Account Balance (T-Account View):**<br>    <table><thead><tr><th>Suspense Account</th><th></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Debit</td><td>Credit</td></tr><tr><td>Opening Balance 420</td><td></td></tr><tr><td>Correction (i) 80</td><td></td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Correction (ii) 800</td></tr><tr><td>Total Debits 500</td><td>Total Credits 800</td></tr><tr><td></td><td><b>Bal c/d 300</b></td></tr><tr><td>800</td><td>800</td></tr></tbody></table><br>The closing balance is **$300 credit**.</p>]]></text></generalfeedback>
    <defaultgrade>1.00</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>true</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>abc</answernumbering>
    <correctfeedback format="html"><text>Your answer is correct.</text></correctfeedback>
    <partiallycorrectfeedback format="html"><text>Your answer is partially correct.</text></partiallycorrectfeedback>
    <incorrectfeedback format="html"><text>Your answer is incorrect.</text></incorrectfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100.00000" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>$300 credit</p>]]></text></answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>$460 credit</p>]]></text></answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>$1,140 debit</p>]]></text></answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>$1,300 debit</p>]]></text></answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name><text>FA2-Ch10-S1-11-PRK6.16</text></name>
    <questiontext format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>Gary owns a grocery store and prepares financial statements to 31 December each year. On 1 January 20X5 he purchased a new delivery van costing $5,000 to use in his business. He incorrectly recorded this as maintenance expenses. Gary has a policy of depreciating vehicles over 5 years and assumes a nil residual value.<br><br>How will the correction of this error affect the profit for the year ended 31 December 20X5?</p>]]></text></questiontext>
    <generalfeedback format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>The following is GenAI explanations, use with caution.This is an error of principle: a capital expenditure (asset) was incorrectly treated as a revenue expenditure (expense).<br><br>1.  **Effect of the Error:** By recording the $5,000 van as a maintenance expense, the profit for 20X5 was reduced by the full $5,000.<br><br>2.  **Correction Steps:**<br>    a.  **Remove the incorrect expense:** The $5,000 maintenance expense needs to be reversed. This will increase profit by $5,000.<br>    b.  **Capitalize the asset and add depreciation:** The van should be recorded as a non-current asset. It must then be depreciated. The depreciation expense for the year is the cost divided by the useful life: $5,000 / 5 years = $1,000. This is a new expense that will decrease profit by $1,000.<br><br>3.  **Net Effect on Profit:**<br>    *   Increase from removing expense: +$5,000<br>    *   Decrease from adding depreciation: -$1,000<br>    *   Net change: +$4,000<br><br>Therefore, the correction of the error will **increase profits by $4,000**.</p>]]></text></generalfeedback>
    <defaultgrade>1.00</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>true</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>abc</answernumbering>
    <correctfeedback format="html"><text>Your answer is correct.</text></correctfeedback>
    <partiallycorrectfeedback format="html"><text>Your answer is partially correct.</text></partiallycorrectfeedback>
    <incorrectfeedback format="html"><text>Your answer is incorrect.</text></incorrectfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100.00000" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>Increase profits by $4,000</p>]]></text></answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>Increase profits by $5,000</p>]]></text></answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>Decrease profits by $1,000</p>]]></text></answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>Decrease profits by $4,000</p>]]></text></answer>
  </question>
  <question type="cloze">
    <name><text>FA2-Ch10-S1-12-PRK6.17</text></name>
    <questiontext format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>Your bank account in the general ledger at 31 December 20X3 shows a bank balance of $565 overdrawn. On comparing this with your bank statement at the same date, you discover the following.<br><br>(i) A bank payment for $57 made by you on 31 December 20X3 has not yet cleared the bank statement.<br>(ii) A cheque for $92 from a customer, which was paid into the bank on 24 December 20X3, has been dishonoured on 31 December 20X3.<br><br>What is the correct overdrawn bank balance to be shown in the statement of financial position at 31 December 20X3</p><p>Answer: {1:NUMERICAL:=657:0}</p>]]></text></questiontext>
    <generalfeedback format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>The following is GenAI explanations, use with caution.The question asks for the correct bank balance to be reported in the statement of financial position, which is the adjusted balance in the general ledger (or cash book). We need to adjust the general ledger for items the business was not aware of until seeing the bank statement.<br><br>1.  **Starting Balance:** The general ledger shows a balance of $565 overdrawn (a credit balance).<br><br>2.  **Item (i) - Uncleared Payment:** A bank payment of $57 has not yet cleared. This means it has already been correctly recorded in the general ledger (as a credit to the bank account), but it hasn't appeared on the bank statement yet. This is a reconciling item for the bank reconciliation statement, but it does **not** require an adjustment to the general ledger balance.<br><br>3.  **Item (ii) - Dishonoured Cheque:** A customer's cheque for $92 was dishonoured. When the cheque was initially received, the business would have debited the bank account by $92. Since the cheque has bounced, this entry must be reversed. The correcting entry is to credit the bank account by $92, which increases the overdraft. The debit will go back to the customer's trade receivables account.<br><br>4.  **Calculation of Corrected Balance:**<br>    *   Starting overdrawn balance: $565<br>    *   Add effect of dishonoured cheque: +$92<br>    *   Corrected overdrawn balance: $565 + $92 = **$657**</p>]]></text></generalfeedback>
    <defaultgrade>1.00</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name><text>FA2-Ch10-S1-13-PRK6.18</text></name>
    <questiontext format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>Elounda is preparing her bank reconciliation. She has noted the following:<br><br>(i) The bank has levied charges on her account.<br>(ii) A bank payment made to S Wright has not yet cleared the bank statement.<br><br>Which of the above errors require an entry in the bank account in her general ledger?</p>]]></text></questiontext>
    <generalfeedback format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>The following is GenAI explanations, use with caution.The general ledger (cash book) must be updated for any transactions that have appeared on the bank statement which the business was previously unaware of. Items that are already in the general ledger but not on the bank statement are timing differences.<br><br>**(i) Bank charges:** These are levied by the bank and appear on the bank statement. The business typically does not know the exact amount until they see the statement. Therefore, an entry is required in the general ledger to record this expense (Debit Bank Charges, Credit Bank).<br><br>**(ii) Uncleared bank payment:** This payment was made by the business and would have already been recorded in the general ledger (Credit Bank) when the cheque was issued. The fact that it has not yet cleared the bank is a timing difference. It is a reconciling item but does not require a new entry in the general ledger.<br><br>Therefore, only item (i) requires an entry in the bank account in the general ledger.</p>]]></text></generalfeedback>
    <defaultgrade>1.00</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>true</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>abc</answernumbering>
    <correctfeedback format="html"><text>Your answer is correct.</text></correctfeedback>
    <partiallycorrectfeedback format="html"><text>Your answer is partially correct.</text></partiallycorrectfeedback>
    <incorrectfeedback format="html"><text>Your answer is incorrect.</text></incorrectfeedback>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>Both (i) and (ii)</p>]]></text></answer>
    <answer fraction="100.00000" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>(i) only</p>]]></text></answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>Neither (i) nor (ii)</p>]]></text></answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>(ii) only</p>]]></text></answer>
  </question>
  <question type="multichoice">
    <name><text>FA2-Ch10-S1-14-PRK6.19</text></name>
    <questiontext format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>Your firm's bank statement at 31 October 20X8 shows a balance of $13,400. You subsequently discover that an electronic payment of $300 received from a customer and recorded in the bank general ledger account on 31 October 20X8 was dishonoured by the customer's bank on 1 November 20X8 and that bank charges of $50 were not recorded in the bank general ledger account. There are uncleared bank payments totalling $1,400. You further discover that an automatic receipt from a customer of $195 has been recorded as a credit in your bank account in the general ledger.<br><br>What was the balance on your bank account in the general ledger before correcting the errors and omissions?</p>]]></text></questiontext>
    <generalfeedback format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>The following is GenAI explanations, use with caution.This question requires working backwards from the reconciled balance to find the original uncorrected general ledger balance.<br><br>1.  **Calculate the Corrected (Reconciled) Bank Balance:** This can be found by adjusting the bank statement balance for timing differences.<br>    *   Bank statement balance: $13,400<br>    *   Less: Uncleared bank payments: ($1,400)<br>    *   Corrected General Ledger Balance = **$12,000**<br><br>2.  **Identify the Adjustments Needed for the General Ledger:**<br>    *   **Dishonoured payment ($300):** This payment was recorded as a receipt on 31 Oct. Although dishonoured on 1 Nov, it relates to the 31 Oct balance and is an adjusting event. The receipt must be reversed. This requires a credit to the bank account, so the adjustment is -$300.<br>    *   **Bank charges ($50):** These were not recorded. This requires a credit to the bank account, so the adjustment is -$50.<br>    *   **Automatic receipt error ($195):** A receipt should be a DEBIT. It was incorrectly recorded as a CREDIT. To correct this, we must: a) reverse the incorrect credit with a debit of $195, and b) post the correct debit of $195. The total adjustment is a debit of $195 + $195 = +$390.<br><br>3.  **Work Backwards to Find the Original Balance:**<br>    *   The formula is: Original GL Balance + Adjustments = Corrected GL Balance<br>    *   Original GL Balance + (-$300) + (-$50) + (+$390) = $12,000<br>    *   Original GL Balance - $350 + $390 = $12,000<br>    *   Original GL Balance + $40 = $12,000<br>    *   Original GL Balance = $12,000 - $40 = **$11,960**</p>]]></text></generalfeedback>
    <defaultgrade>1.00</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
    <single>true</single>
    <shuffleanswers>true</shuffleanswers>
    <answernumbering>abc</answernumbering>
    <correctfeedback format="html"><text>Your answer is correct.</text></correctfeedback>
    <partiallycorrectfeedback format="html"><text>Your answer is partially correct.</text></partiallycorrectfeedback>
    <incorrectfeedback format="html"><text>Your answer is incorrect.</text></incorrectfeedback>
    <answer fraction="100.00000" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>$11,960</p>]]></text></answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>$12,155</p>]]></text></answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>$13,360</p>]]></text></answer>
    <answer fraction="0" format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>$13,750</p>]]></text></answer>
  </question>
  <question type="cloze">
    <name><text>FA2-Ch10-S1-15-PRK6.20</text></name>
    <questiontext format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>A business had a balance at the bank of $2,500 at the start of the month. During the following month, it paid for materials costing $1,000 less trade discount of 20% and taking advantage of the settlement discount of 10%. It received a bank transfer from a customer in respect of an invoice for $200, who took advantage of the settlement discount of 5%, when they had not been anticipated to do so.<br><br>What was the balance at the bank at the end of the month?</p><p>Answer: {1:NUMERICAL:=1970:0}</p>]]></text></questiontext>
    <generalfeedback format="html"><text><![CDATA[<p>The following is GenAI explanations, use with caution.We need to calculate the cash inflows and outflows to determine the closing bank balance.<br><br>1.  **Opening Bank Balance:** $2,500<br><br>2.  **Calculate Cash Payment for Materials (Outflow):**<br>    *   List price of materials: $1,000<br>    *   Trade discount is deducted first: 20% of $1,000 = $200. The invoice price is $1,000 - $200 = $800.<br>    *   Settlement discount is calculated on the invoice price: 10% of $800 = $80.<br>    *   The actual cash paid is the invoice price less the settlement discount: $800 - $80 = **$720** (outflow).<br><br>3.  **Calculate Cash Receipt from Customer (Inflow):**<br>    *   Invoice amount: $200<br>    *   Settlement discount taken by customer: 5% of $200 = $10.<br>    *   The actual cash received is the invoice amount less the discount: $200 - $10 = **$190** (inflow).<br><br>4.  **Calculate Closing Bank Balance:**<br>    *   Opening Balance: $2,500<br>    *   Less: Payment for materials: ($720)<br>    *   Add: Receipt from customer: +$190<br>    *   Closing Balance = $2,500 - $720 + $190 = **$1,970**</p>]]></text></generalfeedback>
    <defaultgrade>1.00</defaultgrade>
    <penalty>0</penalty>
    <hidden>0</hidden>
  </question>
</quiz>